start with one Circle representing the
number one take seven copies of this
circle by placing one in the center and
six around the outer ring like this to
represent the number seven repeat this
process as often as you want taking
seven copies of the previous shape by
placing one in the center and six around
the outer ring this technique produces
visual representations for the powers of
seven to create the visual
representation for 7 to the N we can do
this one more time using seven copies of
the visual representation for 7 to the N
minus one but an alternate way to
produce this same diagram is to take the
sum of the powers of 7 from 1 up to 7
the n minus1 and create six different
copies living around the central circle
once we add the central circle we end up
with the same total number of circles in
the diagram as the one from 7 to the N
therefore 6 * the sum of the powers of 7
from 1 up to 7 the N minus 1 + 1 is
equal to 7 the N this gives us a formula
for the finite geometric sum with ratio